<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Brian S. Hong - Projects</title><link href="https://blog.hongs.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.hongs.me/feeds/projects.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.hongs.me/</id><updated>2019-07-20T14:30:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>BUUL Part 2: Design</title><link href="https://blog.hongs.me/buul-part-2-design.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-07-20T14:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-20T14:30:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian</name></author><id>tag:blog.hongs.me,2019-07-20:/buul-part-2-design.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Design of the JUUL vaporizer clone.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the part two of my vaporizor writeup. You can find part one &lt;a href="/buul-part-1-reversing-the-juul.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note: THIS POST IS INCOMPLETE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This post will go in depth though the design process.&lt;br&gt;
Very in depth, also as if it were almost a tutorial on design and KiCad.&lt;br&gt;
Please &lt;a href="https://thenypost.files.wordpress.com/2014/09/bear1.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;w=606"&gt;bear&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Power Supply&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I know the voltage and how much current it needs to be able to supply, I can start
designing the power supply. Since it needs to output a whopping 6 watts, I decided to go
with a switch mode power supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Types of Voltage Regulators.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I'll discuss a few different types of voltage regulators.&lt;br&gt;
First, there are the linear regulators. They are often quick and easy to use, but can be
very inefficient, espcially for high loads. That is because they act like a voltage divider,
but with feedback and stuff. It's advantages are that it gives a low output ripple and noise.
It's bad for this case because it is highly inefficient, and to make this project portable,
it is going to run off a battery. When a linear regulator is used to lower the voltage, all
that extra power goes directly to heat. For example, If there is a 12 volt input to a 5 volt
regulator, and the load pulls 1 amps, it will draw 1 amp from the 12V supply and dissipate
that as heat. So in this example, it would be something like 7 watts per amp drawn.
(12V - 5V) * 1A  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, switch mode power supplies tend to be more efficient. They work by
&lt;em&gt;switching&lt;/em&gt; the output on and off really quickly and smoothing out the ripple with inductors
and capacitors, until you get the desired voltage. It is similar to how a PWM signal works to
"fake" an analog signal with a digital signals. In fact, I will be using a PWM signal to a
transistor to create a buck converter.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buck converters are a type of switch mode power supplies when the output voltage is lower than
that of the input. Boost converters are used to increase the voltage from a lower source.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Microcontroller&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a microcontroller of some sorts to basically control the vaporizer. A simple operation
would be that it has a button and the coil/power supply connected and would turn the power on
when the button is pressed. I was going to use a buck converter, so the microcontroller should
output the PWM. I did some quick search for cheap and small microcontrollers. I found and decided
to use the &lt;a href="https://www.microchip.com/wwwproducts/en/ATtiny10"&gt;ATTINY10&lt;/a&gt; of the AVR microcontroller
series. These things are tiny and consume very little power, also being perfect for small embedded
projects like this.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ATTINY10 Pinout" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_attiny_pinout.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The above is the pinout diagram of the attiny10  microcontroller. There are two pins for power
(VCC and GND), and a whopping number of 4 GPIOs, which is more than enough. For the basic operation,
we only really need two I/Os, one for the button and another for the PWM output. The other two I/Os
can be reserved for extra functionality. I originally planned to have one for LED and the other
for voltage output feedback, to ensure that the voltage is actually what we want.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at some other features of the attiny10, it's got a programmable timer, two PWM channels,
4 8-bit ADCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Designing a Buck Converter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A basic buck converter looks and works like this:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Buck Converter Diagram" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_buck_converter.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As mentioned above, the output voltage can be changed or set by changing the duty cycle of the
on/off times of the switch. The on-off signal from the switch is then 'smoothed' out via the
LC filter. At first, I was looking to use a built-in switching regulator, but most of them
seemed to need external inductors anyways. And since I'm already using a MCU for the PWM and to
do other stuff as well, I decided to just build a buck converter.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texas Instruments had this document &lt;a href="http://www.ti.com/lit/an/slva477b/slva477b.pdf"&gt;SLVA477B&lt;/a&gt;
on designing the power stage of a buck converter, which was very useful. I just followed through
the calculations to get the desired output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Buck Converter Power Stage" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_buck_converter_sch.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In my design, I replaced the switch with a transistor. I used an PFET instead of NFET since it
will be easier to drive it due to biasing (&lt;a href="https://electronics.stackexchange.com/questions/194634/p-channel-vs-n-channel-in-buck-converter"&gt;stackexchange&lt;/a&gt;).
To choose a transistor, I went on Digikey's parameteric search. I ended up with &lt;a href="https://www.digikey.com/product-detail/en/diodes-incorporated/DMG2305UX-13/DMG2305UX-13DICT-ND/4251589"&gt;DMG2305UX&lt;/a&gt;.
The most important parameters in this case I think were the threshhold voltage and the voltage+current rating.
The current has to be higher than 2 amps. This one can deal with 4.2 amps, to be safe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;[TODO: Insert More Design Stuff and Calculations]&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that and following the TI SLVA477B document, I got roughly all the values I needed for
the buck converter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Schematics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what my entire schematic came out to look like:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="Buck Converter Schematic" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_circuit_sch.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top part is the buck converter and it is basically the circuit shown in the previous section.&lt;br&gt;
I added another 22uF capacitor for more filtering and the microcontroller part is fairly
straightforward. The 10k resistor (R2) is there as a &lt;a href="https://www.electronics-tutorials.ws/logic/pull-up-resistor.html"&gt;pull-up&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
The PWM output pin actually also drives the indicator LED (D2) as well.
This works because the anode is held high so it will light when the output is driven low,
which is when the P-channel MOSFET is turned on.
This has a bonus effect of indicating the power output depending on the PWM duty cycle.
There are two other pins that are connected that I haven't discussed yet, but we'll come back to them later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The capacitor back on the bottom is for decoupling. What that means in this case is that
it "de-couples" the AC noise from the DC signal. When the device is triggered, it starts to
output and the coil will consume about 6W of power, and that is no small amount
(for a circuit like this). When something like that happens, voltage (or current) can't immediately
start to flow and the V_IN voltage will drop. If that drops significantly, it may not be enough
to power the microcontroller. So by having a capacitor bank, it allows the sudden changes to happen
without dropping the input voltage (kinda like having a water tank and then suddenly everyone turns
their faucet on at the same time).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually didn't populate all of these capacitors, but I had a few extra just in case.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that, it was time to do board layout.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait, wait... Just to really make sure before I went through all the troubles, I simulated
the buck converter circuit in LTSpice. If I could just find the files somewhere...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Simulation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I was really unsure about was whether the transistor I picked out can handle
the load and also operate properly in the way I set it up.&lt;br&gt;
Usually, the manufacturers provide models for their components for simulation... in some way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I Googled for "DMG2305UX spice model" and there was one just on the first few hits. (&lt;a href="https://www.diodes.com/spice/download/2275/DMG2305UX.spice.txt"&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
Then I followed the steps &lt;a href="https://www.analog.com/en/technical-articles/ltspice-simple-steps-to-import-third-party-models.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to import that into LTSpice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is the test circuit I drew up:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="LTSpice Schematic" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_ltspice_sch.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, V2 is the power source (the battery) and V1 is the PWM input to the gate of the transistor (U2).&lt;br&gt;
The PWM signal is defined by the long PULSE(blah blah) text, each number corresponding to:&lt;br&gt;
off voltage, on voltage, time delay, rise time, fall time, on time, period, and number of cycles.&lt;br&gt;
In this case, the period is 4e-6 and on time is 3.5e-6 which is a duty cycle of 0.875.
The on and off voltages are reversed because a P-channel MOSFET will turn on "when the gate voltage is low."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From that we can roughly predict what our output voltage is going to be:&lt;br&gt;
Input * (duty cycle) = output = 3.7V * (0.875) = 3.2375V  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I added R1 as the load with 1.6 ohms, which was the measured resistance of the coil.
A citcuit like this won't work properly if there is no load.
If you look at the datasheet for a switching power IC, there will be a minimum load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the simulated waveform:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="LTSpice Output" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_ltspice_output_large.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red plots the PWM signal. Remember that I used a P-channel MOSFET, so it conducts on the low.&lt;br&gt;
The green is the output voltage across the load R1. It rises once the PWM starts and eventually goes to the desired voltage, which seems to be around 3.2V looking at the figure.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simulation files will be available is the GitHub repo as well.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have somewhat verified that this circuit will work, it was time for PCB layout.&lt;br&gt;
(I also built the circuit to test it, but it is normally a good idea to simulate)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PCB Layout&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware next block of text up to the layout diagram.&lt;br&gt;
It's helpful info/tip for people new to this, but will bore you if you're familiar with the process.&lt;br&gt;
If you don't like it, you may skip to the PCB diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing you do after drawing out the schematic would be to annotate and perform a DRC.
In KiCad, the toolbar has a list of tools in order to move onto the PCB layout step.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img alt="KiCad Toolbar" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_kicad_toolbar.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first automaticaly annotates all the components, the second (ladybug) runs electrical rules
check. It will check for unconnected pins are floating nets and such. Although sometimes, there
will be some you can ignore because of how the component pins are defined. For example, when you
have header pins supplying power, it will warn you that there is no power input. That can be fixed
by going to the options and marking that connection to connection type to be valid.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third associates each component with a footprint. Some parts will already have one assigned,
like the ATTINY10 I picked out when I selected the component to put on the schematic.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I'll have to go through each and select a footprint for it for the layout.&lt;br&gt;
After that, I can select the NET button to generate a netlist.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next two are optional if I wanted to create a Bill of Matrials, listing all the components and the part number.
The last button there moves over to the layout program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="BUUL PCB Layout" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/002_layout.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the layout I've come up with. I tried to make the entire thing as small as possible.&lt;br&gt;
I planned on etching this myself, so I tried to fit everything on a single side as I'm not
yet ready to do double sided boards, with the lining up and vias and all that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is enough for the design. I'm gonna end it here.
Might take for a bit for me to write about prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;br&gt;
73,&lt;br&gt;
-Brian&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>BUUL Part 1: Reversing the JUUL</title><link href="https://blog.hongs.me/buul-part-1-reversing-the-juul.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-14T19:30:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-03-14T19:30:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Brian</name></author><id>tag:blog.hongs.me,2019-03-14:/buul-part-1-reversing-the-juul.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A $5 clone of a JUUL vaporizer. I gather information about the JUUL so that I could build one.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, as mentioned in the &lt;a href="/hello-world.html"&gt;Hello World&lt;/a&gt; post, I've recently built a vaporizer
that is supposed to be a clone of the popular JUUL.&lt;br&gt;
It accepts regular JUUL pods (and now MYLE pods as well).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, why did I build it?&lt;br&gt;
So my friend came up to me a few weeks ago, frantically, saying, "BRIAN! I need your help.
I lost my vape. Could you engineer me a new one?!?!"&lt;br&gt;
He ended up buying a new one soon after, but I said, "Challenge accepted!"
(Plus I thought it'd be a fun little quick project to do)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;(Kinda) Reversing the JUUL&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had some ideas in my head. I definitely did not want to make an entire vaporizer from
scratch, and I also wanted it to fit regular pods.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaporizers have 3 major parts: the power supply, the coil, and the tank.
The power supply produces the voltage and current necessary.
The coil receives the power from the supply and heats up.
The tank holds the liquid, which vaporizes from the coil's heat and is then inhaled by the user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Vape Diagram" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/001_vape_diagram.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ok, I tried. I tried to find a good diagram that depicts something like the above diagram,
but couldn't... So I drew my own.&lt;br&gt;
Honestly, now that I look at it, maybe the other diagrams were better...
Well, you're stuck with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The JUUL has (mainly) two parts: the power supply (that's the long silver/black/red meta part)
and the pod (that's replaceable and contains the "e-juice" that gets vaporized)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a picture of a pod:
&lt;img alt="POD Teardown" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/001_pod_teardown.jpg"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conveniently, the pods contain the coil as well, which means I won't have to deal with any of
the coil or the liquids. I've got a hold of a few used pods and took them apart. It's fairly
simple; submerged in the ink is an assembly of a coil wrapped around some wick that pulls the
liquid into the coil.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, trying to figure out how the JUUL works or does the vaporization thingy,
I did some research. It didn't take long at all until I found &lt;a href="https://www.juul.com/intellectual-property-list"&gt;JUUL's patents page&lt;/a&gt;. The first one listed (&lt;a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US9215895B2/en"&gt;US9215895B2&lt;/a&gt;) actually has some cool data and graphs. Most of the other ones are about their
"Vaporization Device Systems and Methods" and different versions of it, but I found
&lt;a href="https://patents.google.com/patent/US10045568B2/en"&gt;US10045568B2&lt;/a&gt; the most useful. It looks
like its got the most recent form for the pod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="JUUL Patent Pod Exploded View" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/001_juul_patent_pod_exploded.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now that's a proper diagram. I don't know how to properly cite a source for a diagram from a patent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="JUUL Patent Pod Diagram" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/001_juul_patent_pod_diagram.png"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Also from the same patent. This diagram looks most like the actual JUUL pod.
I also don't know how to properly size images either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the bottom of the pod are the two contacts that the power pack supplies the power through to
the coil inside the pod. There doesn't seem to be any kind of circuitry besides that inside the
pods themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the earlier versions of the JUUL, seen in the other patents, it seems like they
were planning to add a small microcontroller of some kinds inside the pod for smart operations
and maybe DRM. Probably DRM. Not really DRM, but like, similar. Maybe I should've actually read
the patents. They likely ditched the idea since it would make the pods more costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, back on topic. All I have to do was mimic the JUUL power supply. To do this, I first
need to figure out how much power it provides. To do this, I need to know the voltage and
current. To do &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; I wanted to mimic the pod so that I can plug it into the JUUL and measure
the output. So I did. The resistance across the coil measured through the exposed contacts was
about 1.6 ohms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I've noticed that the JUUL has a short circuit protection. Which is generally a smart idea,
especially for consumer devices and for small gadgets that people put inside pockets and throw
around. When the two pins inside the JUUL are shorted, the LED blinks orange a few times. Okay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that next step was for me to connect 1.6 ohms across the contacts on the JUUL and measure the
output. I've also noticed that when a pod was connected, the LED blinks white once. It must
have some measuring circuit to know when there is a pod inserted. I gutted out the said used
JUUL pods, and after soaking their disassembled parts in alcohol for a few minutes and cleaning
them, reassembled it, only without the coil and two resistors in its place to make ~1.5 ohms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh man, I'm writing this like it's a lab report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Modified JUUL Pod with Resistors" src="https://blog.hongs.me/img/001_juul_pod_mod_resistor.jpg"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So I did that.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it worked.&lt;br&gt;
When I plugged it in, the light lit up once, which indicates that a pod had been plugged in.
I simulated a "pull" and the resistors got hot. I also hooked up a voltmeter across the
resistors during it and it measured about 3.3 volts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great! I have the voltage, and all I need now is the current. I tried to measure the current
that the resistors were drawing. I started by hooking up an ammeter in series, but that
messes with the resistance of the load, so that didn't work. For about a good 30 minutes, I
couldn't figure it out...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I slammed my head on the table. OHM'S LAW! How could I forget. I already had all the
information to get the current draw. I have the resistance and the voltage across it.
Applying Ohm's law, 3.3V / 1.6 Ohms gives me a little over 2 amps. Wow, this thing consumes
over 6 Watts of power! Makes a little sense since all that heat energy is being used to
vaporize the liquids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is kinda getting long and I'm tired. I don't know. Maybe I'll leave this here for now.
Come back for part two for power supply design and possibly prototyping and building it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, the finished (or is it?) design files and code can be found &lt;a href="https://github.com/ME-IRL"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I've made a page for some of the side projects I do. They're all gonna be under the page
&lt;strong&gt;Mechanical and Electrical Industry Research Labs&lt;/strong&gt; aka ME-IRL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;br&gt;
73,&lt;br&gt;
-Brian&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>